Exalogic Product Support Engineer Name: Anilkumar Nallamothu Email: nallamothu.anil@gmail.com Mobile: +91-96119 44557

in.linkedin.com/in/anilkumarnallamothu















#### **SUMMARY**

15 years of experience working in various roles such as Support Engineer, Technical Support Engineer, Systems Analyst, Technical consultant.

Expert on Oracle IaaS Cloud Platform technologies and Engineered Systems - Exalogic, Private Cloud Appliance (PCA), Extensively involved in Product Support, Support to Sustain, Bug Triage, Testing and Release Management activities for Oracle Cloud Engineered Systems.

Knowledge on DevOps process and Tools covering full CI/CD Pipelines, As Git, Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, Kubernetes, and Terraform on both AWS and OCI.

Knowledge on Python, GO languages and Bash scripting.

#### CERTIFICATIONS

- OCI Certified for Architect Associate, Cloud Operations Associate and Foundations Associate.
- Exalogic Elastic Cloud Certified Implementation Specialist.
- Information Technology Infrastructure Library (ITIL) V3 Certificated.
- Sun Certified Java Programmer (SCJP).

#### **EMPLOYMENT DETAILS**

- Working as Principal Software Engineer with **Oracle**, Bangalore from Nov 2016 to till date.
- Worked as Senior Software Engineer with Oracle, Bangalore from Oct 2014 to Nov 2016.
- Worked as Senior Consultant with Cappemini, Bangalore from April 2009 to Sep 2014.
- Worked as Senior Software Engineer with **Datamatics** from September 2006 to Mar 2009.

### **EDUCATION**

- MCA: Computer Applications 2002-05 75% Kingston PG College Hyderabad.
- **BCA**: Computer Applications 1999-02 71% RG Kedia College Hyderabad.
- 10+2: Mathematics, Physics and Chemistry 1997-99 79% MRR Jr. College Kodad.
- **SSC**: Higher Secondary Education 1996-97 79% Sri Mathru Sri Vidyalaya Kodad.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Cloud Technologies** - Oracle IaaS and Engineered Systems – OCI, Exalogic, Private Cloud Appliance **Operating Systems** - Oracle Linux, SUN Solaris, Red hat Enterprise Linux, CentOS

**Programming languages** – Java, C, Python, Go.

Storage - ZFS Storage Appliance, OCI Storage

**Networking** - InfiniBand Switches, Cisco Switches

**Hardware** - x86-64, SPARC, Exalogic, Private Cloud Appliance (PCA)

**DevOps -** Git, Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform

Cloud Platforms - OCI, AWS

Exalogic Product Support Engineer Email: nallamothu.anil@gmail.com
Name: Anilkumar Nallamothu Mobile: +91-96119 44557

Mobile: +91-96119 44557 in.linkedin.com/in/anilkumarnallamothu

## **As Exalogic Support Engineer at Oracle**

Oct 2014 to till Date

Working in Oracle as a Principal Software engineer, which involves direct customer support is also a major facet of the position and includes working with the most sensitive of customer issues including those that are of high priority and severity.

Following are the roles and responsibilities in current Principal Support Engineer designation:

**Product Support**: In this role assist all Customers using Oracle IaaS Cloud Engineered Systems - Exalogic, Private Cloud Appliance (PCA). Member of Oracle Platinum Support and Platinum Patching team supporting Platinum Certified high profile Customers in resolving their mission critical issues related to Infrastructure, assist with patching of Engineered Systems, Backup & Recovery strategy, Upgrades and new installations of Engineered Systems.

**Security Certified Engineer**: Assist Customer with solutions and remediation to complex security vulnerabilities reported on Exalogic and PCA

**Proactive Support Delivery Engineer (PSD):** In this role proactively document any important known issues, best practices, admin guides for Engineered Systems by creating Knowledge Notes, Documentation and White Papers etc.

**Product Testing**: Involved in Engineered Systems Product testing working closely with Development team whenever there are new releases and Patch Set Updates (PSU), which release every quarter.

In addition, as a Cluster Technical Coordinator (**CTC**) for Exalogic, helping many Engineers from different teams and HUB in isolating and triaging the Exalogic issues and get them assigned appropriately.

## **Projects handled for General Motors (Capgemini)**

Infrastructure Management Projects

April 2011 to Sep 2014.

- EOSL (End of Service Life)
- DCT (Data Center Transformation)

General Motors based out of USA and a leading company in automobile industry globally. Supported and maintained a suite of more than 40 General Motors' worldwide web applications, being in the role of onshore/offshore coordinator, Responsible for troubleshooting of production and preproduction problems, including working with 3rd party support, manage deployments and rollbacks of code. GM primarily uses Weblogic and Sun Java Web Server with Oracle databases.

# **EOSL (End of Service Life)**

EOSL (End of Service Life) is a value-added service offering, which uses a structured Factory Approach to bring IT systems up to date with evolving technologies in order to meet changing needs of Business. The objective of EOSL is to make business applications more valuable and serviceable by upgrading their software components to the latest versions and enhancing their performance, security, stability and usability.

Exalogic Product Support Engineer Email: nallamothu.anil@gmail.com

Name: Anilkumar Nallamothu Mobile: +91-96119 44557 in.linkedin.com/in/anilkumarnallamothu

# **DCT (Data Center Transformation)**

The Objective of DCT to migrate all application servers to GM (Own) hosting environment from other vendor hosting environments due to Business reasons, and at the same time utilized the situation for upgrading their software components to the latest versions.

GME-Order Work Bench Retail Application (Release 2)

GME-Order Work Bench Retail Application (Release 1)

GME-Order Work Bench Retail Application (Legacy)

Sep 2006 – Jun 2008

The General Motors European Order Workbench focused within the Sales & Inventory Planning Process area of the RWE (Retail Workbenches and Enablers) vision and specifically focuses on the supporting services required by a dealer to place and manage orders with General Motors Europe.

GME OWB is primarily a web interface to support GM Retailers in the process of configuring and ordering GM vehicles from the dealer perspective. It is integrated with the core GME Order Processing and Vehicle Lifecycle management application in GM\* DRIVE.

### Responsibilities:

- Responsible for the analysis, coding & testing of the objects before delivery to client.
- Part of performance tuning team of GME OWB application.
- Production Code movement and deployment.
- Active participation & effective co-ordination with the client for simulation testing/UAT.
- Responsible for identifying the change and converting it to an RFW.
- Participated in Rollout of OWB for different countries.
- Involved in OWB Health check process automation by using WLST.
- Effective co-ordination with the Dealer Assistance center.
- Application reports preparation and communication with the client.
- Effective co-ordination with IM Vendor team (HP) for regular patch support.

**Environment:** Suse Linux, Weblogic 11g, Eclipse, Java, J2EE, Oracle 11G, PVCS, SVN, ITSM (HP), Remedy, Primus, Renaissance, Clarity, LDAP, MQ Series and VAP Proxies.

Date:	
Place:	(Anil Kumar Nallamothu)